<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Vinícius Krolow</title>
    <link>http://krolow.com.br/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Vinícius Krolow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 01:31:49 -0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://krolow.com.br/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://krolow.com.br/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 01:31:49 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://krolow.com.br/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, you! I&amp;rsquo;m Vinícius Krolow, as the header of the page says&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m a Senior full stack developer with over a decade of experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I&amp;rsquo;m based in the beautiful city of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com.br/search?q=florianopolis&amp;amp;espv=2&amp;amp;biw=1920&amp;amp;bih=938&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjE-Ifyu5vLAhVIjZAKHe1RBDwQ_AUIBygC#tbm=isch&amp;amp;q=florianopolis+praias&#34;&gt;Florianópolis&lt;/a&gt;, living with my wife and 4 dogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m always involved in some learning process, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the things that I most like in the technology field, it&amp;rsquo;s that felling, that we always have something new to learn and to improve ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professionally speaking, you can check my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/krolow/cv&#34;&gt;resume here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://us.linkedin.com/in/krolow&#34;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m open for new opportunities, do not hesitate to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:krolow@gmail.com&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;experience:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main experience is in the backend side, I have worked about 6 years dedicated to backend side, and still the area where I most &lt;strong&gt;shine&lt;/strong&gt;. But, to be completed as a backend developer
you need to know the &lt;strong&gt;whole&lt;/strong&gt; thing, when I say the whole thing, is all the areas that you are working with, like mobile, or the frontend side
of WEB, devops side, etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As knowing the whole thing I have started to also supporting some tasks in the front-end side and I had at the time a good knowledge of javascript, so it was when I got more involved with frontend as well, developing some mobile applications with Objective-C native, as well hybrid apps&amp;hellip; Also got involved in some projects where I as dedicated to frontend side, been full time developer in javascript, it was few years before the term Full Stack have been given for such a role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In general a long of the years I got experience in:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doing the HTML/CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cutting layout from Firworks/Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop desktop applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop Backend API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop crawlers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop single page apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop convertion tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop social apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop CMS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;customize CMS like Wordpress/Drupal/Tyopo3 even create plugins for those&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop distributed systems using microservices architecture, etc..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-focus:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;My Focus&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still enjoy a lot backend side, and it stills the area where I have most experience and I really enjoy to work with, but I
have been also focus in develop single apps applications with React.js, Angular, so that I can take ideas out of paper and implement the
whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really love to learn new things, as I have said before, and I have been dedicated my learning process in new languages (Go, Elixir) and paradigms
like Functional, as well in distributed systems (where I have started a master degree but I didn&amp;rsquo;t conclude because I moved to another city).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These things that I&amp;rsquo;m learning are been my focus to enable me to create applications that scale, and keep the logic simple in the domain that belongs to, and I think new paradigms and languages would help me write a simple code that better describes the given problem that I need to solve, by having more languages and paradigms in my toolkit I can choose what is the best tool for a given task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;keywords-that-i-have-been-using:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Keywords that I have been using&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have used for several projects:&lt;/strong&gt; Angular.js, React.js, Node.js, PHP, Ruby, Javascript, CakePHP, Zend Framework, Symfony 2, ES6, ES2015, babel.js,
MySQL, PgSQL, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Docker, Microservices, MongoDB, Redis, etcd, Java (Android), Redux, Vagrant, Bootstrap, Express, Jquery,
Wordpress&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Have used more than once:&lt;/strong&gt; Python, Flask, Backbone, Asp, ElasticSearch, Lucene, Rx.js, Firebase, Electron, Puppet, Silex, Cilex, Windows
Powerpoint COM, Drupal, Typo3, Rails, Croogo&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Have used at least once:&lt;/strong&gt; Ember.js, Riak, Objective-C, Django, Rails 4, Phonegap, OpenCV, Titanium, Hugo&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Have been learning:&lt;/strong&gt; Go, Elixir&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>